Higher. Further. Faster. Together.
The Marvels is a science fiction, adventure,
action film directed by Nia DaCosta.
When her duties send her to an anomalous wormhole linked to a Kree revolutionary, Carol's
powers become entangled with that of Jersey City super-fan Kamala Khan, aka Ms.
Marvel, and Carol's estranged niece, now S.A.B.E.R.
astronaut Captain Monica Rambeau.
Together, this unlikely trio must team up and learn to
work in concert to save the universe.
Carol Danvers / Captain Marvel, played by Brie Larson.
Monica Rambeau, played by Teyonah Parris.
Kamala Khan / Ms. Marvel, played by Iman Vellani.
Nick Fury, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Dar-Benn, played by Zawe Ashton.
Emperor Dro'ge, played by Gary Lewis.
The Marvels is a 2023 American superhero film based on Marvel Comics.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the sequel
to the film Captain Marvel (2019), a continuation of the television miniseries Ms.
Marvel (2022), and the 33rd film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Nia DaCosta, who co-wrote the
screenplay with Megan McDonnell and Elissa Karasik.
It stars Brie Larson as Carol Danvers / Captain Marvel, Teyonah Parris
as Monica Rambeau, and Iman Vellani as Kamala Khan / Ms.
Marvel, alongside Zawe Ashton, Gary Lewis, Park Seo-joon, Zenobia
Shroff, Mohan Kapur, Saagar Shaikh, and Samuel L.
In the film, Danvers, Rambeau, and Kamala team up as "the Marvels" after they begin
swapping places with each other every time they use their powers.
Marvel Studios confirmed plans to make a sequel to Captain Marvel in July 2019.
Development began in January 2020 with McDonnell hired after
working on the television miniseries WandaVision (2021).
Larson was set to return from the first film as Danvers,
and DaCosta was hired to direct that August.
In December, Parris was revealed to be reprising her role as Rambeau from
WandaVision alongside Vellani returning as Kamala from Ms.
Second unit filming began in mid-April 2021 in New Jersey, and the title—referring to the
three characters and their similar abilities—was revealed in early May.
Principal photography began in July 2021 and concluded by mid-May 2022, taking place at Pinewood Studios in
Buckinghamshire and Longcross Studios in Surrey, England, as well as in Los Angeles and Tropea, Italy.
Karasik's involvement was revealed during post-production.
The Marvels premiered in Las Vegas on November 7, 2023, and was released in the
United States on November 10 as part of Phase Five of the MCU.
It received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for its performances
but criticism for its script and tonal inconsistencies.
The film was a box-office bomb, grossing $206 million worldwide against a gross production budget of $374 million, making it
the lowest-grossing film in the MCU and one of the few MCU films not to break-even in its theatrical run.
The film explores themes of hero, superhero, space
travel, based on comic, sequel.
The tone is thought_provoking.